<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Veli-Pekka Parkkinen on V-P Parkkinen</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Veli-Pekka Parkkinen on V-P Parkkinen</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Veli-Pekka Parkkinen</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Visualizing frscore results, part 1</title><link>/blog/frscore_viz1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/frscore_viz1/</guid><description>This post is the first in a series of short texts about the frscore package, in which I describe upcoming changes in the package itself, and try to give some tips about how to make working with the package more convenient. This post and the next one are about visualizing the output of frscore() and frscored_cna().
Discussing with users of cna, I get the impression that the method is fairly often used specifically to discover or generate hypotheses about interactions between known causes of some outcome of interest.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>I am a philosopher of science working mostly on problems related to theory of explanation, and epistemology of causation. That is, I seek answers to the following kinds of questions: What is it that makes a piece of information explanatory of some event or state of affairs? How does explanation differ from other epistemic outputs of science such as prediction or &amp;ldquo;mere&amp;rdquo; truthful description of the world? How can we reliably learn about what causes what?</description></item><item><title>Publications</title><link>/publications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/publications/</guid><description>Books Parkkinen, V-P., Wallmann, C., Wilde, M., Clarke, B., Illari, P., Kelly, MP., Norell, C., Russo, F., Shaw, B., &amp;amp; Williamson, J. (2018). Evaluating evidence of mechanisms in medicine – principles and procedures. Springer. link
Journal articles Parkkinen, V-P (2022). Variable relativity of causation is good. Synthese, 200(193). link
Parkkinen, V-P. &amp;amp; Baumgartner, M. (2021). Robustness and model selection in configurational causal modeling. Sociological methods and research (online first). link</description></item></channel></rss>